ILGWU Communications Department Biography File Photographs 5780/177 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Communications Department Biography File Photographs
1934- 1990
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/177 P
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Photographs.
This collection consists of photographs transferred from the Communications Department's biographical files on union members, union officers, and political and public figures.
7128117
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 17, 2011
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, September 03, 2015
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
The precursor to the ILGWU's Communications Department was the Publications and Publicity Department. Though the name and scope of the department changed over time, its primary function stayed the same throughout the history of the ILGWU. The department was responsible for the publication of the ILGWU's official publication Justice, as well as the official editions in Yiddish (Gerechtigkeit), Italian (Giustizia), and Spanish (Justicia), and it was also responsible for cooperating with journalists outside of the union on pieces about the ILGWU. Beyond coordinating such efforts of journalists, the Communications Department provided information about the union to other labor organizations, students, and teachers.
Scope and Contents
The records of the Communications Department consist entirely of subject and biographical files, with related photographs. Taken together, these records document ILGWU events, organizations, and leaders, as well as political figures and other prominent labor unionists.
The Communications Department's alphabetical subject files (5780/176) contain clippings from publications that appear to be produced through the Communications Department or with its cooperation. The clippings in this collection provide concise, published accounts of events and affiliates of the ILGWU, as well as of issues of special interest to the union. The related photograph collection (5780/176 P) includes a variety of images documenting the work of the union, arranged in two series: Events and Organizations, and Personalities. These photographs include large groups of people at meetings, protests, and other events, and ILGWU members, staff, and leaders at work.
The Communications Department's biographical files (5780/177) are of interest not only because they provide sometimes difficult-to-find, basic information on ILGWU members and officers, but because that information was provided by the individuals themselves, on forms provided by the union and designed to be returned to the office when completed. These biographical forms appear to have begun as a project of the editors of Justice, and the information contained includes date and place of birth, when the subject arrived in the United States, positions held in the ILGWU or other unions, and outside activities and interests. The related photograph collection (5780/177 P) includes portraits of some of the individuals represented in the biographical files, as well as photographs of events and miscellaneous photographs.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/176: ILGWU Communications Department Records 5780/176 P: ILGWU Communications Department Photographs 5780/177: ILGWU Communications Department Biography Files
Women's clothing industry -- New York (State); Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Industrial relations -- New York (State); Allen, Meyer; Appleton, Shelley; Berger, Martin, b. 1929; Berger, Solomon; Bialis, Morris; Bonanno, Nicholas; Borax, Fannie; Bruno, Joseph; Chaikin, Sol C.; Chmielowiec, Philip; Clinton, Bill, 1946-; Cristofaro, Michelangelo; Curtis, John W.; Daniels, Wilbur; Delgado, Ricardo; Diamond, Moe; Dolgen, Abe; Dubrow, Evelyn; Fisher, Joseph; Flack, Sol; Fontaine, Robert; Friedman, Joseph; Germer, Adolph; Goldberg, Sol, 1923-; Gonzalez, Manuel; Goze, Irving; Horowitz, Joseph; Hughes, Ruby; Kaplan, Milton; Kirkland, Lane; Kramer, Edward; Labby, Manly A.; Lemlich, Clara, 1886-1982; Longo, Frank; Mazur, Jay; Melamed, Jerome; Milano, Edward; Molisani, E. Howard; Montenegro, Lou; Moynihan,Daniel P.(Daniel Patrick), 1927-2003; Nemaizer, Samuel; Newman, Pauline; Orsini, Raymond; Paladino, Morris; Paris, George; Ramirez, Julius; Romney, Edgar; Rosenberg, Edward; Rufer, Harry; Saladino, Sam; Sanchez, Alberto E.; Schoenwald, Matthew; Schuster, Mary Goff; Sciuto, Anthony; Siems, Frederick Rolle, 1915-; Solomon, Irwin; Songer, Margaret; Sosa, Peter G.; Stein, Leon, 1912-; Strongin, Paul; Teper, Lazare, 1908-; Tischler, Charles; Ulene, John; Weiss, William; Windman, Nat; Zeldin, Sam; Zuckerman, Rubin; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Communications Dept
7128117
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Jerry and Hillary, Vermont Office, Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- VDT hearing (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Washington choice rally/demonstration, Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Matawan, Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Matawan/Aberdeen School District Unit Meeting, Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Scope and Contents
  Fall 1989
- Matawan Aberdeen victory, Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  September 15, 1989
- Hispanic Labor Committee dinner honoring Noemi Terres (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Chosun demonstration, Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  October 17, 1990
- [National Life Campaign, VDT training, Vermont], 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- ILGWU Convention, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Postcard negatives (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Labor Day, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- DuBois CTB victory party, Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE) (Box 1, Folder 24)
- CTB negotiations (Melanie and Stacie) (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Labor Day, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Operator at Machine (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Convention, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Photographs
- Convention '86 [2], 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- 1986 ILGWU Convention (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Allen, Meyer (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Photograph
- Appleton, Shelley, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Berger, Martin, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Bialis, Morris, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Photograph; March
- Bonanno, Nicholas, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Photograph; September/October
- Borax, Fannie (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Borowick, Moe (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Bruno, Joseph, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Chaiken, Sol C. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Chmielowiec, Philip (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Clinton, Bill (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Cristofaro, Michelangelo (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Curtis, John W. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Daniels, Wilbur (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Delgado, Ricardo (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Diamond, Moe (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Dolgen, Abe, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Dubrow, Evelyn, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Fisher, Joseph, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Flack, Sol (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Fontaine, Robert, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Friedman, Joseph (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Germer, Adolph (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Photograph; Founder of the CIO
- Goldberg, Sol, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Gonzalez, Manuel, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Goze, Irving (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Horowitz, Joseph (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Photograph; So. New England
- Hughes, Ruby (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Kaplan, Milton (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Kirkland, Lane, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Kramer, Edward, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Labby, Manly A., 1959 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Lemlich, Clara (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Longo, Frank, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Mazur, Jay (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Melamed, Jerome, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  Photograph; Local 190
- Milano, Edward, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Molisani, E. Howard (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Montenegro, Lou, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Nemaizer, Samuel, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Newman, Pauline, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Orsini, Raymond (Box 2, Folder 49)
  Local 91; Photograph
- Paladino, Morris (Box 2, Folder 50)
  Photograph; Local 91
- Paris, George (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Ramirez, Julius, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Romney, Edgar (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Rosenberg, Edward (Box 2, Folder 54)
  Photograph, Local 190
- Rufer, Harry, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Saladino, Sam (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Sanchez, Alberto E., 1981 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Schoenwald, Matthew, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Schuster, Mary Goff (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Sciuto, Anthony (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Siems, Frederick R. (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Solomon, Irwin (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Songer, Margaret (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Sosa, Peter G. (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Stein, Leon (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Strongin, Paul (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Teper, Lazare (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Tischler, Charles (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Ulene, John (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Weiss, William (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Windman, Nat (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Zeldin, Sam (Box 2, Folder 72)
- Zuckerman, Rubin (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Unknown (Box 2, Folder 74)